<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Yosua Ian Sebastian's blog</title><link>https://darcien.dev/tags/note/</link><description>Recent posts in my blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 21:28:02 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darcien.dev/tags/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Picking Paid Live Stream Platform as Viewer</title><link>https://darcien.dev/p/picking-paid-live-stream-platform-as-viewer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 21:28:02 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://darcien.dev/p/picking-paid-live-stream-platform-as-viewer/</guid><description>Short note comparing between available live stream platform</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="platforms">Platforms</h2>
<h3 id="eplus">eplus</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://ib.eplus.jp">https://ib.eplus.jp</a></p>
<p>Last watched: 2023-03-18, hololive 4th fes</p>
<p>Rating: avoid if possible 👎</p>
<p>Okay-ish for watching the live stream.
Unuseable for watching the archives.
Getting a bunch of audio issues on the archives like noises and out of sync,
after a while, no audio plays.</p>
<h3 id="hololive-official-fanclub-subscribe-only-with-no-one-time-ticket-kinda-counts">hololive official fanclub (subscribe only with no one time ticket, kinda counts)</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://hololive-fc.com">https://hololive-fc.com</a></p>
<p>Last watched: 2023-06-21, variety show with Asaka as guest</p>
<p>Rating: decent but no choice on exclusive content 😐
(Firefox user: bad site 👎)</p>
<p>A relatively new hololive exclusive platform, showed up at early 2022.
Suprisingly decent considering it&rsquo;s their own platform
and doesn&rsquo;t have the same problem with Niconico even though they list Dwango
in the footer<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Their website feels weird though with all commenters&rsquo; name feels
generated
(2023-06-17: Seems like this is no longer the case, names are no longer bot-like).
And most of the videos views and comments are weirdly exact multiples of thousand.</p>
<p>Also, they stopped supporting Firefox on 2023-05-30<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>.
Which is a sad thing, but not a dealbreaker.</p>
<h3 id="niconico-dwango">Niconico (Dwango)</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://live.nicovideo.jp">https://live.nicovideo.jp</a></p>
<p>Last watched: 2023-03-15, Nornis 1st live</p>
<p>Rating: paid for video, only got the audio 😭</p>
<p>Same old nico nico douga but with different name.
Functionally, it&rsquo;s great.
Pratically, I can&rsquo;t like it.</p>
<p>Last time I watched Nornis&rsquo; live, it&rsquo;s still stutter on lowest stream quality.
I don&rsquo;t know if what&rsquo;s causing it, but Niconico connection to Indo has never
been good regardless of ISP.
Plus, to watch archive (Timeshift in Niconico) you need to subsribe to their
premium service(2023-06-17: cost JPY 550 per month).</p>
<h3 id="spwn">SPWN</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://virtual.spwn.jp">https://virtual.spwn.jp</a></p>
<p>Last watched: 2022-03-20, hololive 3rd fes</p>
<p>Rating: pretty safe choice if available 👍</p>
<p>So far the most platform I&rsquo;ve been using and has the least problem with.
From time to time has bad connection to Indo
even after turning on low latency mode on their video player.</p>
<h3 id="youtube-member-only-live-kinda-counts">YouTube (member only live, kinda counts)</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://youtube.com">https://youtube.com</a></p>
<p>Last watched: pretty much every month</p>
<p>Rating: probably the live you want to watch is not here 😔</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s YouTube.
They probaby have the best infra for running live stream in the world right now.</p>
<p>But they don&rsquo;t run ticketing for one-time watch.</p>
<h3 id="z-an">Z-aN</h3>
<p>Link: <a href="https://www.zan-live.com">https://www.zan-live.com</a></p>
<p>Last watched: 2023-06-17, Planet Station stage 8</p>
<p>Rating: my new go to platform 🫶
(Firefox user: Booo, please fix the video player 🤕)</p>
<p>First time watched on Z-aN, surprisingly a great platform!
Good to the point it become a trigger for me to make this notes.
From registration flow, payment (it uses Stripe at the moment), stream connection,
archives, even bonus digital goods from buying tickets, this Z-aN tick all the boxes.</p>
<p>My only gripe is Z-aN is unusable on Firefox.
Works smoothly on Vivaldi so I have not tried other browsers.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="/img/zan-on-firefox-fail.jpg#center"
         alt="Z-aN video player fail with `The m3u8 file loaded file` error message"/> <figcaption>
            <p>On Firefox, after few mins the video player will error out, needing a page refresh</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="/img/zan-date-byte.png#center"
         alt="Showing date input with &#39;Please enter your date of birth as a single-byte number.&#39; from Z-aN registration flow"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Bonus: Z-aN wants me to enter my date of birth as a single-byte number, I have no idea how to convert a date into a single byte.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="backstory">Backstory</h2>
<p>Starting to lose track with the many live streaming platform out there.
So I created this note to avoid using the bad ones if possible.
Most of the time there&rsquo;s no choices though.
Even when there are choices, at most it&rsquo;s 2, it&rsquo;s pick bad or the less bad one 🥲.</p>
<hr>
<p>Post 13 of <a href="https://100daystooffload.com/">#100DaysToOffload</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p>2023-06-17: Web archive for hololive-fc.com does not load for me right now.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230617152311/https://hololive-fc.com/">https://web.archive.org/web/20230617152311/https://hololive-fc.com/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230617155122/https://hololive-fc.com/notification/114">https://web.archive.org/web/20230617155122/https://hololive-fc.com/notification/114</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Monitor Notes</title><link>https://darcien.dev/p/monitor-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 19:18:21 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://darcien.dev/p/monitor-notes/</guid><description>A diary of boring adventure in setting up monitors. Also works as a timecapsule letter, dear future me, don&amp;rsquo;t repeat these mistakes.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="monitors-used">Monitors Used</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dell U2417H [24&quot; 60Hz IPS Monitor]</li>
<li>ViewSonic XG2431 [24&quot; 240Hz IPS Monitor]</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="macos--viewsonic-issues">MacOS + ViewSonic Issues</h2>
<p>Can&rsquo;t use random USB-C cable + USB hub for connecting ViewSonic to M1 MacBook Air running Big Sur.</p>
<p>Mac detected the monitor, but monitor show &ldquo;no signal&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Maybe cable or hub issue? Used the same exact cable and hub with different monitor, worked.</p>
<p>Maybe monitor port issue? Used same HDMI port with Windows desktop, worked.</p>
<p>Then I found this review on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/review/R19FF79H8JO7G9/ref=cm_cr_srp_d_rdp_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07JVKS8JQ">Amazon</a> for different ViewSonic model:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Other reviewers here have noted all the pros about this monitor, I will just add that 1-) the adjustable stand is especially easy to use and useful for long hours and avoiding neck pain and 2-) reminder that they ship only a display port/USB cable and an HDMI cable with it even though monitor is USB -C enabled. if you are running Mojave 10.14 or later the adapters for display port and HDMI simply will not work, the mac book will never see the monitor. You <em>must</em> get a USB-C 3.1 to C cable. Then you can just plug it all in. Also need to add a shout out to Anne at Amazon (complimentary) tech support for helping figure all this out by coordinating with ViewSonic because it wasn&rsquo;t documented anywhere at the point at which I was trying to do it. Thank you Anne!</p>
<ul>
<li>bookkook, 2019 March</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Hey, that problem sounds familiar.</p>
<p>So I just learned there&rsquo;s a lot of USB-C variant, and USB-C 3.1 gen 2 is a thing.</p>
<p>Currently ordering a new cable, will update later.</p>
<p>Update: It&rsquo;s 2022 and I bought a new cable.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.ventioncable.com/product/usb-c-to-hdmi-cable-2/">HDMI to USB-C from Vention</a>.
Surprise! It worked! I&rsquo;ll skip the story of the package courier miss-deliver the cable and I had to buy it twice.</p>
<p>After using it a full day without problems, I realized a fatal miss when it&rsquo;s time to charge the laptop.
Macbook air only have 2 USB-C ports! 1 for monitor, and the other one for USB hub, this is for keyboard etc. and I can&rsquo;t work without it.</p>
<p>Okay, back to square one. I tried rummaging through my jumbled mess cable collection and found a HDMI to HDMI cable.
Not sure where it&rsquo;s from, maybe from Nintendo Switch.
It looks exactly like your average HDMI cable, and it&rsquo;s pretty old, but there&rsquo;s no harm in trying it right?</p>
<p>Another surprise! I have zero idea why, but connecting that old HDMI cable to the USB Hub and it worked! Mac could properly detect the monitor now.
The only thing I can identify from the cable is E202584 AWM from a company called Linkiss.</p>
<p>In a way, I wasted a total of IDR 319K for unused cables and few hours to look into the cause.
What I learnt from this:</p>
<ul>
<li>I have no idea how HDMI works</li>
<li>I have even less idea how USB C works</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="windows--monitors-with-mixed-hdr-mode">Windows + Monitors with Mixed HDR Mode</h2>
<p>Windows 10 with multi-monitor, but only some of them have support HDR.</p>
<p>If HDR is enabled on supported monitors, this will break preview feature from Windows on non-HDR monitor. E.g. win+tab will show black desktop and windows, hovering on running program from taskbar will show black window instead of actual preview.</p>
<p>Solution, turn off HDR :(</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Device List</title><link>https://darcien.dev/p/devices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:38:10 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://darcien.dev/p/devices/</guid><description>List of devices that I use, mainly to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t forget that I (used to) own these things.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>List of devices that I use, mainly to make sure I don&rsquo;t forget that I (used to) own these things.
The year is the approximate year I obtained them.</p>
<p>They&rsquo;re listed in alphabetical order.</p>
<h2 id="functional">Functional</h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple iPhone X 256GB [Handphone] (late 2018) -&gt; my daily driver, perfect fit for my hand.</li>
<li>Apple Watch Series 3 42mm [Smartwatch] (early 2021) -&gt; heartbeat and general physical activity tracker, at least it&rsquo;s cheaper than Garmin&rsquo;s.</li>
<li>Audio Technica ATH-M50x [Headphone] (~2016) -&gt; best general use headphone IMO.</li>
<li>Dell U2417H [24&quot; IPS Monitor] (mid 2018) -&gt; I love this monitor, might buy another one if my old monitor dies.</li>
<li>Endgame Gear XM1r [Wired Mouse] (early 2022) -&gt; I don&rsquo;t know why this is marketed as gaming mouse, but this is my perfect casual mouse and it has just right weight.</li>
<li>HP W2072a [20&quot; TN Monitor] (~2012) -&gt; one of my earliest monitor, still going strong!</li>
<li>ViewSonic XG2431 [24&quot; 240Hz IPS Monitor] (late 2021) -&gt; impulsive purchase, first time looking at monitor with high refresh rate, recommended by a friend.</li>
<li>KBParadise V80 Vintage MX Brown switch [Keyboard] (late 2018) -&gt; I won&rsquo;t go back to full sized keyboard.</li>
<li>Lenovo B40-70 [Laptop] (mid 2015) -&gt; from my uni, avoid this thing if possible, the frame is weaker than a rice cracker.</li>
<li>Logitech M325 [Wireless Mouse] (early 2014) -&gt; decent mouse with ridiculous lifetime.</li>
<li>Nintendo Switch Lite [Game Console] (mid 2019)* -&gt; why I can&rsquo;t dock it :&lt;</li>
<li>Nintendo Switch v2 [Game Console] (late 2020) -&gt; it can docks :D</li>
<li>ORICO SHC-U3 4 Port [USB Hub] (mid 2020) -&gt; some cheapo USB 3.0 hub, I need more ports.</li>
<li>Pioneer XDP-30R [Digital Audio Player] (early 2019) -&gt; awesome HQ audio player for the price, it also got mechanical volume dial, I love it!</li>
<li>Rock DT-618 [Wireless Charger] (late 2018) -&gt; kinda meh, slow charge and heats up after awhile.</li>
<li>Samson Meteor Mic [Condenser Microphone] (late 2017) -&gt; decent portable condenser mic, sadly it&rsquo;s USB only though.</li>
<li>Sony DualShock 4 v2 CUH-ZCT2 [Wireless Gamepad] (~2016) -&gt; you can&rsquo;t have a dead cable if you don&rsquo;t have any cables ;)</li>
<li>Sony SRS-XB10 [Wireless Speaker] (late 2018) -&gt; got it for free, pretty decent mono speaker.</li>
<li>Sony WH-1000XM3 [Wireless Headphone] (late 2018)* -&gt; pretty good noise cancelling, sadly not a good match with my ear shapes.</li>
<li>Yamaha AG06 [Audio Interface] (late 2020) -&gt; a godsent for managing all of my audio inputs, I also love its mechanical interface.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="needs-fixing">Needs Fixing</h2>
<ul>
<li>OnePlus One 16GB [Handphone (early 2016) -&gt; used to be flagship killer, need new battery.</li>
<li>Sony PSP-3000 [Game Console] (~2010) -&gt; need to replace the membrane for the buttons, power switch kinda broken, screen also have dead pixel lines.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="not-sure">Not Sure</h2>
<ul>
<li>Nintendo Game Boy Advance SP AGS-001 [Game Console] (~200x) -&gt; the display brightness sucks, also the chargers keep dying.</li>
<li>Nintendo Game Boy Color CGB-001 [Game Console] (~200x) -&gt; probably still works, need AA batteries though.</li>
<li>Nintendo SNES North American SNS-001 model [Game Console] (~200x) -&gt; not sure if this thing still alive or not, this thing is older than me.</li>
<li>Samsung C3590 [Handphone] (~2013) -&gt; fav flip phone, haven&rsquo;t used it for years.</li>
<li>Sennheiser HD202 [Headphone] (~2014) -&gt; probably still works, haven&rsquo;t used it again since M50x.</li>
<li>Sony PlayStation PS1 original model [Game Console] (~200x) -&gt; same, no idea about this one after all these years.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="dead">Dead</h2>
<ul>
<li>HP Mini 110 (I think, I forgot if it&rsquo;s 110 or 210, but it&rsquo;s the 10'1&quot; screen) [Notebook] (~2010) -&gt; dead HDD and battery, half dead monitor, not worth repairing.</li>
<li>Logitech F310 Gamepad [Gamepad] (~2013) -&gt; dead cable, then I fked up when soldering the new one.</li>
<li>Nokia C7-00 [Handphone] (~2011) -&gt; handed off to family member, dead battery etc.</li>
<li>Sennheiser CX 1.00 [Earphone] (early 2016) -&gt; probably just dead cable, but not worth repairing.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="not-yet-owned-aka-wishlist">Not yet owned AKA wishlist</h2>
<ul>
<li>Bluray player -&gt; Already owned a bunch of bluray discs but can&rsquo;t play them :(</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>
<ul>
<li>* - no longer using them, for sale.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>