<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Yosua Ian Sebastian's blog</title><link>https://darcien.dev/tags/writingexperiment/</link><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:52:09 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darcien.dev/tags/writingexperiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My 2022 Without Context</title><link>https://darcien.dev/p/my-2022-without-context/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:52:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://darcien.dev/p/my-2022-without-context/</guid><description>Would writing out past events with less context help me see it more objectively? A writing experiment!</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thought about making this while laying on the bed, so it probably won&rsquo;t make much sense.
I&rsquo;ll do it anyway because that&rsquo;s what I do here.</p>
<p>They are in no particular order and might grow when I remember more things.</p>
<p>In 2022:</p>
<ul>
<li>I paid someone to get some laser shot into my eyes.</li>
<li>I decided to sleep under the same roof with my parents again.</li>
<li>I bought a spinning iron so I can ride my bicycle inside my bed room.</li>
<li>I bought a black chair that feels better than my white chair.</li>
<li>My fear become a reality, I feel alone even with other people around.</li>
<li>I overused my hands and fingers to the point I can&rsquo;t move.</li>
<li>I rode a big truck together with my motorbike and 2 strangers.</li>
<li>I spent like 90% of my time within 2 meter radius of my bed.</li>
<li>I bought a keyboard that looks broken to a layman from Hungary.</li>
<li>I bought a bag made of weed&rsquo;s legal cousin. Haven&rsquo;t arrived yet though.</li>
<li>I took a day off just to find a plastic card.</li>
</ul>
<p>Yeah, some of these sounds pretty crazy if you&rsquo;re missing the context.
This might be a good way to start a conversation.
I need to try this on someone from the office tomorrow.</p>
<hr>
<p>Post 3 of <a href="https://100daystooffload.com/">#100DaysToOffload</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>